Guide to the Ralph Bunche papers
New York Public Library
- Howard University, 1928-1941
  HOWARD UNIVERSITY (1928-1941). Divided into correspondence and office files and arranged alphabetically, materials in this series reflect the scope of Bunche's activities during his tenure at this institution. Included are class syllabi, students' examinations and grades, lecture notes, reports and printed matter. Correspondents include Saul Bellow, Rupert Emerson, Melville Herskovits, Benjamin Azikiwe, and many of his colleagues at Howard: E.P. Davis, Emmett Dorsey, Mordecai Johnson, Charles H. Wesley, Frederick Wilkinson and Eric Williams.
  - Correspondence
    - A (Box 24, Folder 1-2)
    - B (Box 24, Folder 3-4)
    - C (Box 24, Folder 6-7)
    - D (Box 24, Folder 8-9)
    - E (Box 24, Folder 10-11)
    - G (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - H (Box 24, Folder 13-14)
    - I (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - K (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - L (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - M (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - N-P (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - P (Box 24, Folder 20-22)
    - R (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - S (Box 25, Folder 2-4)
    - T (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Unidentified (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - U-V (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - W (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - Office Files
    - Alumni Association (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - The Amenia Conference (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - American Federation of Teachers (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - American Association of University Professors (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Applications (prospective teachers) (Box 25, Folder 13-14)
    - Athletic and recreational activities (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Awards (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Books (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Book orders (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Budget, Department of Political Science (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Budgets, books, departmental expenses (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Colonial policy (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Davis, E. P., College of Liberal Arts (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Davis, E. P., the Graduate Division (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Disciplinary (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Dorsey, Emmett E. (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Education and National Defense Committee (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Enrollment (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Examinations (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Faculty (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Grades, students, 1931-1936 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Grades, students, 1937-1941 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Grades, students, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - The Graduate Council (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - The Graduate School (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - The Italo-Ethiopian Conflict, background study (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Joint Committee on National Recovery, 1935 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Lecture and class notes (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Librarian, W. Daniel (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Lucy Moten Fellowship (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - National Negro Congress (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Newsletter (Howard U., Oct. 1939 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Notebook: “Citizenship and Suffrage” (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Political science majors, 1937 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Political Science Department (Box 27, Folder 12-13)
    - Printed matter (Box 27, Folder 14-15)
    - Purchase orders (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Reading lists (Box 27, Folder 17-18)
    - Registrar (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Reports (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D. Petition to, 1938 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Social Science Division (Box 28, Folder 3-5)
    - Student papers (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Student Council (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Thompson, Charles H. (Box 28, Folder 8)
- Carnegie-Myrdal Study, 1938-1941
  CARNEGIE-MYRDAL STUDY. This series consists of correspondence, draft manuscripts and typescripts of memoranda written by Bunche, as well as interviews, reports and field notes prepared by Bunche, Myrdal and a staff of assistants and collaborators. This material is arranged into four subseries: research and administrative correspondence and memoranda, arranged alphabetically and chronologically; research memoranda prepared by Bunche; reports, field notes and research materials filed by the name of their creators; reports, field notes and research materials filed by city, by county or by state; and printed matter. The memorandum on “Negro Leadership” is incomplete, while separate files exist for each chapter of the lengthy “Programs, Ideologies, Tactics and Achievements of Negro Betterment and Interracial Organizations,” along with questionnaires and questionnaire analyses prepared for the study. Principal contributors to this series, in addition to Bunche and Myrdal, include George Stoney, Whilhelmina Jackson and James Jackson. Major surveys were conducted in St. Louis and Kansas City (Missouri); Jackson, Vicksburg and Natchez county (Mississippi); Birmingham, Huntsville, Godsen and Tuskegee
  (Alabama); Chattanooga, Tuscalooga and Nashville (Tennessee); Cleveland and Dayton (Ohio); Augusta, Atlanta, Savannah and Putnam County (Georgia); Charleston, the Sea Islands, Columbia, Winston-Salem and Greensville (South Carolina); Jacksonville, Tampa and Miami (Florida); and in Little Rock, Chicago, Minneapolis and Oklahoma City. Materials collected include voting charts, annotated city maps indicating segregated boundaries, campaign literature, newsletters and pamphlets.
  - Correspondence
    - 1939 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - 1939-1940 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - 1940-1941 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - Bunche to Alva Myrdal (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Davis, Harry (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Johnson, Guy (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - McKinney, G.W. (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Myrdal, Gunnar (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Norgren, Paul (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Sterner, Richard (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Stoney, George (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Stouffer, Samuel (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - Thomas, Dorothy (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - Whitten, Richard (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Administrative Correspondence
    - Budget (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - Jackson, Wilhelmina (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - Personnel (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Rowena Hadsell (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Research Memoranda by Bunche
    - “A Brief and Tentative Analysis of Negro Leadership” (Box 30, Folder 2-7)
    - “Types of Negro Leadership” (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - “Conceptions and Ideologies of the Negro Problem” (Box 30, Folder 9-10)
    - “Conceptions and Ideologies of the Negro Problem” (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - “Political Status of the Negro,” Voting in the Cotton Referenda (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - “The Programs, Ideologies, Tactics and Achievements of Negro Betterment and Interracial Organizations”
      - First draft (Box 31, Folder 3)
      - “Civic Protest, Betterment...” (Box 31, Folder 4)
      - Commission on Interracial Cooperation (Box 31, Folder 5)
      - District of Columbia Interracial Commission (Box 31, Folder 6)
      - “Constructive Suggestions” (Box 31, Folder 7)
      - “General Critique of Negro Organizations” (Box 31, Folder 8)
      - “Independent Local Organizations” (Box 31, Folder 9)
      - “Independent Local Organizations in Negro Communities” (Box 31, Folder 10)
      - The Jewish Labor Committee (Box 31, Folder 11)
      - “Liberal and Left-Wing Organizations” (Box 31, Folder 12)
      - “Miscellaneous Negro Organizations” (Box 31, Folder 13-14)
      - “The NAACP, National Urban League,” Drafts of chapters (Box 31, Folder 15)
      - Questionnaires on Negro organizations (Box 32, Folder 1-7)
      - “The NAACP,” Drafts of chapters (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - National Negro Business League (Box 33, Folder 2)
      - National Urban League (Box 33, Folder 3)
      - Negro Cooperative Guild (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Outlines (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - Questionnaires (Box 33, Folder 6-7)
      - Questionnaire analysis (Box 33, Folder 8-11)
      - The Universal Negro Improvement Association (Box 33, Folder 12)
      - “Working Guide Memorandum” (Box 33, Folder 13)
      - Corrigenda (Box 33, Folder 14-17)
  - Field Notes, and Research Materials
    - Boas, Franz: “Race: America's Social Barrier” (Box 33, Folder 18)
    - Bunche, Ralph
      - “Charts of Population Voting,” Southern states, 1936 (Box 33, Folder 19)
      - Interview with Mrs. Roosevelt, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 20)
      - Birmingham notes (Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Southern trip (Box 34, Folder 2-3)
      - Negroes and the vote (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Bunche & Myrdal: Field notes, Southern trip (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Bryant, William: Slave revolts and the Negro Convention (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - Cahn, Z.: “The Jewish Phase in the Negro Problem” (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - Cayton, Horace: “Negro Migration” (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - Fleming, James: “The Negro Press” (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - Franklin, Bostic: “Memphis Where the Black Balance of Power Fails to Get the Fruits of Victory” (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Grant, Davis (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - Gross, Bella: Black nationalism (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - Harris, A.: Memoranda (Box 34, Folder 13)
    - Jackson, James
      - Arkansas (Box 34, Folder 14)
      - Kansas City, MO (Box 34, Folder 15)
      - Oklahoma (Box 35, Folder 1)
      - Jackson, MS (Box 35, Folder 2)
      - Nashville, TN (Box 35, Folder 3)
    - Jackson, Wilhelmina
      - Augusta, GA (Box 35, Folder 4)
      - Brunswick, GA (Box 35, Folder 5)
      - Darien, GA (Box 35, Folder 6)
      - Savannah, GA (Box 35, Folder 7)
      - Waycross, GA (Box 35, Folder 8)
      - Jacksonville and Tampa, FL (Box 35, Folder 9)
      - Miami, FL (Box 35, Folder 10)
      - St. Petersburg, FL (Box 35, Folder 11)
      - Charleston and the Sea Islands, SC (Box 36, Folder 1)
      - Columbia, SC (Box 36, Folder 2)
      - Greenville, SC (Box 36, Folder 3)
      - Winston-Salem, SC (Box 36, Folder 4)
      - “Southern Plantation” (Box 36, Folder 5)
      - Research notes (Box 36, Folder 6)
    - Jones, A. Butler: “Negroes in Atlanta” (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - Jones, A. Butler: Atlanta, GA (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - Kester, Howard: Arkansas (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - Lewis, Emmanuel Judge: Savannah, GA (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - Myrdal, Gunnar
      - Bibliographies (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - Field notes, Chicago and Minneapolis (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - Interviews (Box 36, Folder 13-16)
      - “Memorandum on the Disposition of the Study on the American Negro” (Box 36, Folder 17)
      - Methodological memoranda (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - Norgren, Paul: Memoranda (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - Raper, Arthur
      - Buffalo, NY. Interviews (Box 36, Folder 20)
      - Cleveland, OH (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Dayton, OH (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Sterling,?: Little Rock, AR (Box 37, Folder 3)
    - Sterner, Richard: Southern trip. (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Stoney, George
      - Bibb County, AL (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Birmingham, AL (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Gadsden, AL (Box 37, Folder 7-8)
      - Huntsville, AL (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - Tuscaloosa, AL (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Tuskegee, Macon County, Dallas County, Montgomery, AL (Box 37, Folder 11)
      - Beaufort & Charleston Counties, SC (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Burke County, GA (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Dougherty, Ware, Chatham and Johnson Counties, GA (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Gainsville, Greensboro, GA (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Noxubree County, MS (Box 38, Folder 5)
      - Putnam County, GA (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Saluda and Greenville, SC (Box 38, Folder 7)
      - Sumter and Pickens County, SC (Box 38, Folder 8)
      - Certified lists (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Interviews (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - “One Third Democracy for One Sixth of the Nation” (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Notes on the Southern Policy Committee meeting (Box 38, Folder 12)
      - The Poll Tax (Box 38, Folder 13)
      - Charts: Election and Poll Tax lists (Alabama, Georgia) (Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Alabama, research material (Box 39, Folder 2)
    - Whitten, Richard: New Orleans. (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Subject Files
    - Alabama, clippings (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Anti-Lynching Bill, Senate Hearings, (William Bryant), 1940 (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Bibliography, Africa (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Discrimination memorandum (D. Thomas) (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Chattanooga, TN (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - District of Columbia, Reorganization Proposal (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Instruction to field researchers (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Little Rock, AR (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Memphis. TN (Box 39, Folder 12)
    - Natchez, MS (Box 39, Folder 13)
    - “Negro Office Holders” (Crisis) (Box 39, Folder 14)
    - Petersburg, VA (Box 39, Folder 15)
    - “The Police in a Southern City” (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - Statesville, Salisbury, Wilksboro, SC (Box 39, Folder 17)
    - St. Louis, MO (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - South Carolina -- Elections (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - Vicksburg, MS (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - Voting Laws in the South. Research notes and reviews of books and periodical literature. (Box 40, Folder 4-5)
  - Printed Matter
    - Clippings (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Tennessee -- Democratic primary, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 7-8)
    - Tennessee -- Democratic primary, 1939 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Tennessee -- Repeal of the Liquor Law, 1939. (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Tennessee -- Absentee voters' supplies (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - Tennessee -- County Elections, 1938 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Africa, French colonies (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - General (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Commission on Interracial Cooperation (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - NAACP Report, American Fund for Public Service, 1930 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - Alabama -- Elections, 1940 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - General (Box 41, Folder 10-13)
    - Newspapers (oversize)
    - Maps (oversize)
- Trusteeship Council, 1946-1950
  TRUSTEESHIP COUNCIL (1946-1950). Working papers and mimeographed reports of the Trusteeship Council (1946-1950). Committee Four of the General Assembly (the Trusteeship Council) appointed a Sub-Committee of seventeen members, in 1946, to examine and make recommendations to the Fourth Committee on trusteeship agreements proposed for the mandated territories by the corresponding colonial governments. Working papers leading to the formation of the Sub-Committee, proceedings of its 26 meetings, the proposed agreements, in addition to amendments and modifications, statements and resolutions from the various delegations, are included in the files of the Sub-Committee. A major part of this series consists of the complete verbatim records of the 81 meetings of the Trusteeship Council at its sixth session in 1950. Also included are petitions from civic and political associations in the mandated territories challenging colonial rule on such issues as forced labor, abuse of authority and trade-union restrictions.
  - United Nations General Assembly. Fourth Committee Working Papers, Nov-Dec.
    - Statements by the Chairman (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Speeches by Delegates (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Procedures (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - List of Representatives (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Speakers inscribed (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Committee notices (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Communications (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Corrigenda: Journals (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - List of documents (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Press (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Roll call forms (voting materials) (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Sub-Committee reports (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Reports (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Agenda (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Agreements (Box 44, Folder 15-16)
    - Modifications (Box 44, Folder 17)
  - First Session of Sub-Committee One
    - 4th Meeting (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - 5th Meeting (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - 6th Meeting (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - 7th Meeting (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - 8th Meeting (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - 9th Meeting (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - 10th Meeting (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - 11th Meeting (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - 12th Meeting (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Meetings 13-20, 25-27 (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - 21th Meeting (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - 22th Meeting (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - 23th Meeting (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - 24th Meeting (Box 45, Folder 10)
    - Proposed Agreement: Western Samoa (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - Proposed Agreement: British Togoland (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Proposed Agreement: British Cameroons (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Proposed Agreement: Tanganyika (Box 45, Folder 14)
    - Proposed Agreement: New Guinea (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Proposed Agreement: French Togoland (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Proposed Agreement: French Cameroons (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Proposed Agreement: Ruanda-Urundi (Box 45, Folder 18)
    - Draft Trusteeship Agreements: Modifications (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - Draft Trusteeship Agreements: Amendments and modifications (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Draft Trusteeship Agreements: Statements and resolutions (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Reports (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Trusteeship Council, Third Session. Journal, Jun. 1948-Jun. 1949 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Trusteeship Council Documents. Sixth Session, Jan.-Apr. (Volume I-IV)
  - Trusteeship Council Documents. Sixth Session, Jan.-Apr. (Volume V-IX)
- Awards, Membership and Tributes, 1927-1984
  AWARDS, MEMBERSHIP AND TRIBUTES (1927-1984). This series consists of correspondence, certificates, programs, invitations and souvenir journals of luncheons, testimonial dinners and banquets held in Bunche's honor, in addition to documents relating to various memorial tributes and commemorative events following his death. The latter category includes the Ralph Bunche Memorial at the United Nations, the Ralph Bunche Institute of the United Nations at the Graduate School and University Center of the City University of New York, the Ralph Bunche School, the Peace Form One Memorial Project, the Ralph Bunche Memorial at the New York Hospital-Cornell Medical Center, and the “Peace to One” musical tribute by Oscar Brown, Jr. Also included are a letter from President Lyndon Johnson to Bunche awarding him the Presidential Medal of Freedom in 1963, and a letter from U.N. Secretary General U. Thant to Mrs. Bunche awarding a posthumous Peace Medal to her husband in 1972.
  - Correspondence (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Certificates, memberships and awards (Box 49, Folder 2-4)
  - Commencement exercises (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - School appearances and awards (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - “Ralph Bunche, World Servant,” English Teaching Study Unit (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Ralph Bunche Memorial (United Nations) (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - “A Tribute to a Man of Peace,” Lincoln Center, Feb. 27, 1972 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Memorial tributes and obituaries (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - “Peace Form One” Memorial, 1980 (Box 50, Folder 1-2)
  - Other memorial projects (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Programs in honor of Ralph Bunche (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Oscar Brown, Jr. “Peace To One” Musical tribute (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Ralph Bunche Stamp (U.S.) (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Ralph Bunche Community School dedication, 1967 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Certificates (oversize)
- Scrapbooks, 1930-1971
  SCRAPBOOKS (1930-1972): the Howard University Scrapbook which consists of memorabilia and press clippings, 1930-1939; Ruth Bunche's Art Student Scrapbook, 1934-1935; the “Voices of American Liberty” Scrapbook presented to Ralph Bunche at Lord and Taylor's Nineteenth Annual Luncheon on March 18, 1956; the Ralph Bunche Hall Scrapbook at the University of California at Los Angeles; the Jane Bunche Pierce Memorial Scrapbook(1966) consisting of condolence letters, telegrams and sympathy cards, following her death in 1966 (3 volumes); the Ralph Bunche Memorial Scrapbook(1971 - 1972) and the “Peace Form One” Scrapbook(1980) marking the dedication ceremony of the Ralph Bunche Memorial Monument near the United Nations. The Ralph Bunche Memorial Scrapbook consists of seven separate volumes. The first five volumes contains telegrams, sympathy cards and letters of condolence, with attachments, arranged alphabetically. Volume 6 includes obituaries, memorial tributes, registers and printed matter. Volume 7 consists of condolence letters with attachments received by U.N. General Secretary U. Thant, with carbon copies of his replies.
  - Howard University, 1930-1939 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - “Voice of American Liberty,”, 1956 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - “Albuquerque Salutes Ralph Bunche, 1962 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - “Peace Form One Memorial,”, 1980 (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Ralph Bunche Hall, UCLA (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Ruth Bunche Art Student Scrapbook, 1935
  - Ralph Bunche Memorial Scrapbook, 1971-72 (Volume I-II)
  - Ralph Bunche Memorial Scrapbook, 1971-72 (Volume III-IV)
  - Ralph Bunche Memorial Scrapbook, 1971-72 (Volume VI)
  - Ralph Bunche Memorial Scrapbook, 1971-72 (Volume V, VII)
  - Ralph Bunche Memorial Scrapbook, Index of condolences, 1971-72
  - Jane B. Pierce Memorial Scrapbook, 1966. (Volume I)
  - Jane B. Pierce Memorial Scrapbook, 1966. (Volume II)
  - Jane B. Pierce Memorial Scrapbook, 1966. (Volume III)
- Printed Matter, 1931-1975
  PRINTED MATTER AND CLIPPINGS (1931 - 1971) relates primarily to Ralph Bunche, his family life and his career at the United Nations.
  - Clippings
    - Articles re RJB (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Obituaries (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Ralph Bunche, Jr. (Box 62, Folder 3)
    - Ruth Harris Bunche and family (Box 62, Folder 4)
    - The Crisis, Special issue on RJB, 1972 (Box 62, Folder 5)
    - Articles by RJB (Box 62, Folder 6)
    - Reviews of The Political Status of the Negro in the Age of FDR, 1975 (Box 62, Folder 7)
    - Reviews of Peggy Mann's biography of RJB (Box 62, Folder 8)
    - RJB's Nobel Peace Prize (Box 62, Folder 9)
    - Bunche in India (Box 62, Folder 10)
    - Bunche in the Middle East (Box 62, Folder 11)
    - Bunche at the United Nations (Box 62, Folder 12-13)
    - Dag Hammarskjold (Box 62, Folder 14)
    - General (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - General (Box 63, Folder 1-4)
  - Publications
    - “Proceedings in the General Assembly of the United Nations in Connection with the Acceptance of a Gift from the Ford Foundation for the United Nations Library,”, 1959
    - Ralph Bunche, “The International Trusteeship System” in Peace on Earth, New York: Hermitage House, 1949.
    - Articles by and about Bunche in several publications.
    - Articles by and about Bunche in various publications.